RACHEL WHITE

CONTACT

0487600616

rachelizawhite@gmail.com

SUMMARY

After working in data research for 5 years I studied programming to change my career. I discovered an interest in the creative side of programming and am interested in Application Development. I am a fast worker and adaptable to different workplaces, my friendly demeanor and calm presence even when under pressure allows for smooth teamwork and great client service.

SKILLS

Python

C#

SQL, MongoDB Javascript HTML, CSS Wordpress PHP, Laravel

Git Excel

EDUCATION

North Metro TAFE 2022, in progress

Diploma of Information Technology (Back End Web Development)

North Metro TAFE 2021

Certificate IV in Programming

University of Adelaide 2014

Study abroad exchange program under biology degree Recipient of exchange scholar award

University of British Columbia (UBC) 2011-2015

Bachelor of Science in Applied Biology Major in Applied Animal Biology

GITHUB

https://github.com/rae-el

WORK EXPERIENCE

Island Market, Trigg

September2021-present

Server, bar-back. High-end table service for an a la carte menu and coffees. Skills utilized: speaking to customers, 3 plate carry, making cocktails, barista

Sea Around Us Project, UWA, Nedlands & UBC, Vancouver

September2015-June2016, June2017-January2018, March2019-December2020 Researcher. Global fisheries literature and data research. Excel reconstruction of fisheries catch annually, by fishing country, zone, species, gear type, etc.. Large data queries. Data publication. Workshop Speaker. Administration.

2019/20 – UWA researcher, global fishery catch and effort database updates, publications of data research, assisting with Masters students, webpage management, administration assistance (booking flights, workshop organization, etc.)

2017/18 – UBC researcher, reconstructing global baitfish catch 2015/16 – UBC research assistant, global fishery catch database updates

Centre for Marine Futures, UWA, Nedlands

November2016-May2017, February2018-February2019

Laboratory Technician. Baited-remote-underwater-video (BRUV) analysis 2018/19 – laboratory assistant, BRUV analysis and data organization/collection 2016/17 – laboratory assistant, primarily BRUV analysis

.... just ask if you're curious about my other experience

PUBLICATIONS

White, R., Coghlan, A. R., Coulter, A., Palomares, M. L., Pauly, D., & Zeller, D. (2018). Future of Fishing for a Vulnerable Atoll: Trends in Catch and Catch-Per-Unit-Effort in Tokelau's Domestic Marine Fisheries 1950–2016. *Frontiers in Marine Science*, *5*, 476. Data reconstruction, manuscript drafting and editing.

Coghlan, A. R., **White**, R., Dawson, T. P., Irving, R. A., Zeller, D., & Palomares, M. L. (2017). Reconstructed Marine Fisheries Catches at a Remote Island Group: Pitcairn Islands (1950–2014). *Frontiers in Marine Science*, *4*, 320.

Data reconstruction, manuscript drafting and editing.

Christ, H.J., **White**, R., Vianna, G.M.S., Zeller, D. (<u>2020</u>). A baseline for the Blue Economy: catch and effort history in the Republic of Seychelles' domestic fisheries. *Frontiers in Marine Science*, *7*, 269.

Data reconstruction, manuscript drafting and editing.

Vianna, G. M. S., Hehre, J., **White**, R., Hood, L., Derrick, B., & Zeller, D. (<u>2020</u>). Long-Term Fishing Catch and Effort Trends in the Republic of the Marshall Islands, With Emphasis on the Small-Scale Sectors. *Frontiers in Marine Science*, *6*, 828. Data analyzing and manuscript editing.

Pattiaratchi, C. et al. (2022). Plastics in the Indian Ocean – sources, fate, distribution and impacts. *Ocean Sci., 18, 1*.

Manuscript contribution.